Flat no.301, Anusha Pearl, Moti Nagar, Hyderabad, 500018

ANKIT BAJPAI

M: (+91) 7680069007

ankitbajpaib070@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/ankit-bajpai-50498a98

github.com/AnkitBajpaii

Executive Summary

Ambitious technology professional with 4+ years in developing and maintaining multi-tiered, service oriented and client-server windows/web based solution using .NET Framework and Microsoft technology stack.

- Strong in OOP, Design patterns and have good problem solving skills.
- Worked on MVC and MVVM architectural patterns.
- Worked on Prism framework for creating modular application with Unity based dependency injection.
- Hands on experience with ICTS product (Integrated Commodity Trading Systems).
- Experience working with different software process methodologies like Agile & Waterfall Model.
- Interested in challenging technical track career in an application development environment.
- Able to quickly learn new tools and technologies, if need arises.

Technical Skills

Languages: C#(proficient), Core Java(prior experience), Javascript(prior experience)

Frameworks: .NET, ASP.NET, WPF, Bootstrap

Architectural Patterns: MVC, MVVM

Libraries: PRISM, jQuery

Data Access: ADO.NET, Entity Framework, iBATIS

Mark Up: HTML, XAML
Web Services: ASMX, WCF
Third Party: DevExpress, Xceed
Database: Microsoft SQL server

Tools: Visual Studio, Eclipse, ANTS Profiler

Application Server: JBOSS, IIS Source Control: TFS, GitHub

Educational Details

 10^{th} CBSE , Maharishi Vidya Mandir, 72.6 % 12^{th} CBSE , St. Xavier's High School, 82.4%

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) in Computer Science & Engineering – 2012, NIT CALICUT

Work Experience

Amphora Inc. Hyderabad, Aug-2015- Present (Product Based)

Industry: CTRM/ETRM Product Suite: Symphony Oil Role: Senior Software Developer

As a developer I worked on different products under Symphony suite which include :

- ✓ TradeCapture: Rich UI interface to handle all multi commodity & financial trade types like futures, options etc
- ✓ Logistics : Rich UI interface to manage global shipment, storage , inventory of multi commodity in real time.
- Commercial Accounting: Rich UI interface to generate and manage partial cost, to vouch multiple invoices etc.

✓ Dashboards: For middle office users to get different reports as per business requirement. Wrote stored procedures as per business scenarios.

Responsibilities:

- Designed rich UI using XAML and WPF leveraging MVVM architectural pattern for windows based apps.
- > Used Prism framework for creating modules with Unity based dependency injection.
- Used third party components like Xceed, DevExpress etc for rich user experience.
- Used Data binding from UI to model classes and implemented commands and command handling using Prism framework.
- > Implemented server side business logic and database layer using C# and Core Java.
- Written web services in .net and java as per business.
- Developed responsive web pages and layouts using ASP.NET MVC5, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, AJAX for web based applications.
- Implemented Data Access Layer using Entity Framework to connect, retrieve and update data from SQL server.
- Developed stored procedures for the data retrieval and generating reports based on business requirements.
- Adhered to SOLID Principles while designing and implementing entities.
- Tuned up the performance of applications by finding potential code smells, memory leaks using ANTS Profiler.
- Interaction with Business Analyst to get in depth knowledge on business requirement

Infosys Limited, Hyderabad May 2013 - Aug 2015

Project 1:Reserve Serve Client:American Express Role:Developer

An agile project with different online platforms provided for the customers. Every customer holding a serve account is provided with an option to create a reserve account for the very same account which would be served as savings for any planned occasions of the customer.

- Extensively used C#, ASP.NET MVC5 with Razor views for developing web pages.
- Worked on front end styling & layout, using HTML, Bootstrap.
- Used Javascript and JQuery for client side validations.
- Developed reusable class libraries and Ajax based web pages.
- Used LINQ for querying, sorting, filtering complex objects leveraging entity framework.
- > Implemented server side business logic and data layer using C#.
- Developed web services using ASP.NET and stored procedures required for the system to interact with database.
- Implemented Data Access Layer using Entity Framework to connect, retrieve and update data from SOL server.
- Browser Cache busting for JS files using MVC bundling optimization.

Project 2: FCAT Automation Client: Charles Schwab Role: Coded UI Developer

An agile project that dealt with automation of functional and regression test cases Charles Schwab windows and web applications.

- Automated close to 1500 functional and regression test cases using C# skills covering core functionalities using coded UI custom control search thus reducing the manual effort.
- Creating and extending Functional Integration Coded UI framework in case of new application in project.
- Involved in high level feasibility analysis of all the test cases for each application.
- Performed Data Driven, Keyword Driven testing to test application with unique test data.

Training at Infosys Limited, Mysore Mar 2013 - May 2013

Project: Health Care Management System **Role:** Developer

A web based application which is comprehensive enterprise-wide software, which covers all aspects of hospital management and day-to-day operations of a hospital. Accessibility of all information is role based.

Skills used: C#, ASP.NET Web Forms, AJAX, Web Services, ADO.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL

I hereby declare that all the information given above is best of my knowledge.

Date: Place: Hyderabad Ankit Bajpai